in this video we will go over the steps
you will need to complete to set up the
environment on your computer to use the
same dcmqi as a first step you will need to
install docker on your system once you
have completed that step you can issue
the docker pool command to retrieve the
dcmqi image from the docker hub this
will take some time but eventually this
process will complete and the library
will be available for use on your
computer to verify that installation
completed successfully
you can issue docker image ls command to
confirm that the image has been
installed after that you can run the
entry point of the container by issuing
the run command and pass in the name of
the converter he would like to use to
the run command as we discussing the
tutorial later
next we will need to install the 3D
slicer application which is the free
open-source platform for image
visualization and processing please use
the nightly build version and download the
package on your computer once download
is completed you will need to unpack
this package and drag the application to
your application folder if you're using
Mac once 3D Slicer is installed we will
also need to install certain extensions
that are designed to help you visualize
the data generated by dcmqi
to do that he will need to open extension
manager and search for quantitative
reporting extension the dependences of
quantitative reporting will be installed
automatically and include dcmqi extension
you can also install TCIA browser which
is an extension that provides the
interface to the cancer imaging archive
of the National Cancer Institute it can
be handy to retrieve sample data sets
that we will use in the tutorial
finally the last tool that you can
install he is the atom editor atom is a
modern editor which is extensible via
plugins and we provide a plug-in that
allows you to look into the content of
dicom data this plugin can be helpful to
explore the objects that you create as
part of the conversion while using dcmqi
search for the dicom dump package in
the install packages menu of the item
browser item editor install the package
and once you've done that go to the
settings and make sure that path to the
dcmtk installation that is listed in the
settings option of the editor is
populated with the path as shown on the
screen